Pavel Kirilin

Full-stack Developer / Moscow, Russia / Email: kirilin.pav@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pkirilin / GitHub: https://github.com/pkirilin / Portfolio: https://github.com/pkirilin / Portfolio: https://pkirilin.github.io / Portfolio: https://pkirilin.github.io

Summary

Software developer with 5+ years of experience mainly on the .NET stack and knowledge of modern front-end technologies (React, Angular). For the last couple of years have been developing web applications and integration REST APIs based on cloud solutions (Microsoft Azure). Also developed small APIs and scripts using Node.js.

Skills

C# | .NET | ASP.NET Core | Entity Framework Core | MySQL | PostgreSQL | Docker HTML | CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Redux | Node.js | ExpressJS

Experience

Dodo Brands / https://dodobrands.io / Moscow, Russia

An international franchise, which is developing food brands in over 19 countries around the world using IT.

Developer (Jan 2021 - Present)

- Designed, documented, and developed 6 API endpoints used to integrate the corporate system with third-party solutions (accounting systems, bots, CRMs, and SaaS services) and expand its capabilities.
- Implemented the MVP of the applications marketplace service from scratch within 2 months, enabling franchisee
 partners to search and install applications from a range of vendors to customize the system based on their
 needs.
- Automated the process of gathering the technical support team performance metrics from 2 third-party SaaS services by developing a dashboard that is able to show metrics and identify issues with the team's work. This automation saves support managers 2-3 days per week of collecting that data manually.
- Improved the technical support team's efficiency and SLA by 8% through the implementation of a support bot to automate their daily operations.

Super Brands / Moscow, Russia

A distributor of more than 12 world brands of clothing, footwear, and accessories for over 15 retailers in Russia.

.NET developer (Jul 2019 - Oct 2020)

- Reduced the time spent on sending orders to the internal accounting system by 12% through changing the existing integration from SOAP to REST.
- Decreased the time spent on searching and navigating export files by 5% through adapting the functionality of importing and exporting products in Excel format for new data format.
- Provided technical support to the brand management team of 5-8 people and solved 10% of existing bugs based on their feedback.

Quorum / Moscow, Russia

An integrator with 20 years of experience providing IT solutions for over 40 financial institutions in Russia.

.NET developer (Nov 2018 - Jun 2019)

• Reduced the time spent on processing loan applications by 15% by developing and supporting the application for automating the banking loan pipeline using biometric technologies.

Education

Bauman Moscow State Technical University / https://www.bmstu.ru / Moscow, Russia BASc, Informatics and Computer Science (Sep 2014 - Jun 2018)
Robotics and Complex Automation, Computer-Aided Design and Engineering

Additional information

- Languages: Russian (native), English (upper-Intermediate)
- Citizenship: Russian Federation